Inventory of the Howard A. Reed papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- University of Connecticut file (Folder 68-70)
  - University correspondence (Folder 69)
    - Carbon copies, 1979-1980 (Folder 69: 1-2)
    - Inter-office memoranda, 1979-1980 (Folder 69: 3)
  - University of Pennsylvania Middle East Studies Center, 1977-1978 (Folder 69: 4)
  - International Undergraduate Studies notes, 1977 (Folder 69: 5)
  - Financial records (Folder 70)
    - Budget, 1980-1981 (Folder 70: 1)
    - Travel account, 1980-1981 (Folder 70: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1987 (Folder 70: 3)
- Subject file (Folder 70)
  - American Association of University Women, 1985 (Folder 70: 4)
  - American Universities Field Staff (AUFS) report, 1974 (Folder 70: 5)
  - Americans for Middle East Understanding brochures, 1988 (Folder 70: 6)
  - Exxon, 1978 (Folder 70: 7)
  - International Institute for Education Planning (IIEP) newsletter, 1988 (Folder 70: 8)
  - Magazines, 1971-1977 (Folder 70: 9)
  - Middle East and Islamic studies, 1971-1977 (Folder 70: 10)
  - Nuclear war, weapons, and energy, 1980 (Folder 70: 11)
  - Oil, 1974 (Folder 70: 12)
  - Peace, 1978-1989 (Folder 70: 13)
  - Universities Field Staff International (UFSI), 1986 (Folder 70: 14)
- Printed matter (Folder 70)
  - Current Issues in Higher Education, American Association for Higher Education, 1965 (Folder 70: 15)
  - Canadian Society of Muslims report, 1978 May (Folder 70: 16)
- Middle East Journal correspondence, 1968-1969 (Folder 71: 1)
- American Friends in the Middle East, 1968-1971 (Folder 71: 2)
- Middle East miscellany, 1968 (Folder 71: 3)
- Soviet propaganda in the Middle East, Foreign Broadcast Information Service special report, 1969 (Folder 71: 4)
- Student papers, 1983 (Folder 71: 5)
- Sam Gejdenson correspondence, 1983 (Folder 71: 6)
- Middle East Studies major, 1980 (Folder 71: 7)
- Letters received while researching in Switzerland, 1973 (Folder 71: 8)
- Letters received while researching in Turkey, 1973 (Folder 71: 9)
- University of Connecticut file (Folder 71-78)
  - Institute for Intercultural and International Studies (Folder 71-72)
    - Middle East Studies Center. Guest speakers and seminars, 1979 (Folder 71: 10-11)
    - Middle East Studies Group (Folder 71)
      - General newsletters and announcements, 1976-1977 (Folder 71: 12)
      - Newsletter notes, 1977 (Folder 71: 13)
      - Notes and biographies, 1976-1977 (Folder 71: 14)
      - Information on Whirling Dervishes, 1971-1972 (Folder 71: 15)
    - Middle East Studies Program/Middle East Studies Council (Folder 72)
      - Article on languages in University of Connecticut Chronicle, 1979 (Folder 72: 1)
      - Library holdings on the Middle East, 1978 (Folder 72: 2)
      - Announcements, resumes, and other materials, 1975-1979 (Folder 72: 3-4)
      - Speakers and guest lecturers (Folder 72)
        - Ahmed, Sherifa, 1978 (Folder 72: 5)
        - And, Metin, 1978 (Folder 72: 6)
        - Banuazizi, Ali, 1979 (Folder 72: 7)
        - Eisenstadt, S. N., undated (Folder 72: 8)
        - Faksh, Mahmud, 1977 (Folder 72: 9)
        - Frye, Richard, 1975 (Folder 72: 10)
        - Garsoian, Nina, 1978 (Folder 72: 11)
        - Ghaffar Ahmed, Abdul, undated (Folder 72: 12)
        - Ghilan, Maxim, undated (Folder 72: 13)
        - el-Husseini, Hatem, 1977 (Folder 72: 14)
        - Jabber, Paul, 1982 (Folder 72: 15)
        - Kagitcibasi, Cigdem, 1977 (Folder 72: 16-17)
          Relates to value of children and senior citizens in Turkey
        - Mayhew, Christopher, 1977 (Folder 72: 18)
          Includes compact sound cassette of Mayhew on "Obstacles to Peace in the Middle East," 1977 October 25
        - Mirak, Robert, 1978 (Folder 72: 19)
        - Mitchell, Richard, undated (Folder 72: 20)
        - Okyar, Osman, 1981 (Folder 72: 21)
        - Rosen, Steven, 1977 (Folder 72: 22)
        - Rosenberg, Philip, 1977 (Folder 72: 23)
        - Singer, Israel, 1976-1977 (Folder 72: 24)
        - Smith, Walter B., II, 1977 (Folder 72: 25)
        - Touma, Emile, 1976 (Folder 72: 26)
  - America-Mideast education and training services, brochures, undated (Folder 73: 1)
  - American Council on Learned Societies Newsletter, 1965-1976 (Folder 73: 2)
  - American Professors for Peace in the Middle East, 1977 (Folder 73: 3)
  - Assoctiation of Arab-American University Graduates, Inc., 1977 (Folder 73: 4)
  - International studies directories and bibliographies, 1974 (Folder 73: 5)
  - Turkish Studies Association, 1974 (Folder 73: 6)
  - Correspondence and personnel files, 1975-1981 (Folder 73-75:)
    - A, 1979 (Folder 73: 7)
    - B, 1980-1981 (Folder 73: 8)
    - C, 1979-1980 (Folder 73: 9)
    - D, 1978-1979 (Folder 73: 10)
    - E, 1978 (Folder 73: 11)
    - F, 1979-1980 (Folder 74: 1)
    - G, 1978-1980 (Folder 74: 2)
    - H, 1979-1980 (Folder 74: 3)
    - I, 1980 (Folder 74: 4-6)
    - J, 1980 (Folder 74: 7-11)
    - K, 1975 (Folder 74: 12-13)
    - L, 1975 (Folder 74: 14-20)
    - M, 1978-1981 (Folder 74: 21-23)
    - N, 1978 (Folder 74: 24)
    - O, 1979-1980 (Folder 74: 25)
    - P, 1979-1980 (Folder 75: 1)
    - P, 1980 (Folder 75: 2)
    - R, 1979-1980 (Folder 75: 3)
    - S, 1979-1980 (Folder 75: 4)
    - T, 1979-1980 (Folder 75: 5)
    - U, 1978-1980 (Folder 75: 6)
    - V, 1980 (Folder 75: 7)
    - W, 1978-1980 (Folder 75: 8)
    - Y, 1981 (Folder 75: 9)
    - Z, 1979 (Folder 75: 10)
  - Undergraduate International Studies Program (UISP) grant funding documents, 1981 (Folder 75: 11)
  - Resumes, course descriptions, and other materials relating to Middle East Studies program, 1979-1981 (Folder 76: 1)
  - F3C (History), 1979 (Folder 76: 2)
    Includes an assortment of correspondence, course outlines, and research materials relating to language and international studies programs in Connecticut and at the University of San Diego
  - Grant applications for foreign curriculum consultant and relations materials, 1979 (Folder 76: 3-4)
  - Niki Gamm writings, correspondence, and other materials relating to Ottoman history and research, 1980 (Folder 76: 5)
  - Research Foundation-Middle East Studies colloquia, 1980 (Folder 76: 6)
  - Proposals for Office of Education regarding graduate and undergraduate programs, undated (Folder 76: 7)
  - Files relating to U.S. Office of Education (USOE) grant for Undergraduate International Studies Program (UISP), 1979-1981 (Folder 77)
    Includes draft of UISP final report, grant application documents, and correspondence and speeches regarding National Defense Education Act, Title IV
  - UISP abstracts, 1979 (Folder 78: 1)
    Includes drafts
- Turkish Studies file (Folder 78-80)
  - Printed matter relating to Turkey, Turkish poetry, and Turkish studies in the United States, 1968-1983 (Folder 78)
  - Development Foundation of Turkey, 1972-1977 (Folder 79: 1)
  - Institute of Turkish Studies, 1985-1986 (Folder 79: 2)
  - Robert College (Folder 79)
    - Archives, 1961-1985 (Folder 79: 3)
    - Correspondence of Caleb Gates, 1920 (Folder 79: 4)
      Photocopies
    - President's reports, 1927-1928; 1960-1961 (Folder 79: 5)
  - Encyclopedia articles on majlis and madrasas, undated (Folder 79: 6)
  - University of Connecticut. Exams and student papers, 1983-1984 (Folder 79: 7)
  - Newsletters, 1973-1984 (Folder 79: 8)
  - Articles, essays, and other papers relating to Turkey and the Middle East, 1963-1982 (Folder 78: 9)
  - Turkey and Middle East bibliographies, undated (Folder 79: 10)
  - Middle East Institute Library, undated (Folder 79: 11)
  - Notes on lecture by Wayne Vucinich on Serbian nationalism, 1974 May (Folder 79: 12)
  - Bulletin of the International Education Project, 1974 (Folder 79: 13)
  - HIST 284 course list, undated (Folder 79: 14)
  - Near East Mission bulletins, 1973 (Folder 79: 15)
  - American Historical Association, 1974 (Folder 79: 16)
  - Omer Lutfi Barkam notes, undated (Folder 79: 17)
  - Book lists, 1973 (Folder 79: 18)
  - Millet Meclisi, 1972 (Folder 79: 19)
  - Notes, 1967 (Folder 79: 20)
  - Aramco magazine, "Science: The Islamic Legacy,", undated (Folder 79: 21)
  - United Nations Development Program in Turkey correspondence, 1973 (Folder 80: 1)
  - Society for Religion in Higher Education (SRHE), 1974 (Folder 80: 2)
  - Stone, Frank A., 1973 (Folder 80: 3)
  - Szyliowicz, Joseph, 1970 (Folder 80: 4)
  - Howard Reed biography and professional summary, 1972 (Folder 80: 5)
  - Turkish studies lists and addresses, notes, 1984 (Folder 80: 6)
  - Shaw, S. J., 1965-1974 (Folder 80: 7-8)
  - Stamps, 1984 (Folder 80: 9)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1986 (Folder 80: 10)
    Includes slides
  - Student PhD theses, 1958 (Folder 80: 11)
  - Turkish Studies Association, 1973 (Folder 80: 12)
  - Meeting minutes from Hacettepe University, 1963 (Folder 80: 13-14)
- Printed matter (Folder 80)
  - The Nationalization of Arabic and Islamic Education in Egypt. Cairo Papers in Social Science, 1983 December (Folder 80)
  - Greene, Joseph N., Jr. et al. The Path to Peace: Arab-Israeli Peace and the United States: Report of a Study Mission to the Middle East, 1981 October (Folder 80)
  - Western Civilizations course study guide, 1980 (Folder 80)
- Turkish Studies file (Folder 81)
  - Kemal Karpat (University of Wisconsin), 1974 (Folder 81)
  - University of Chicago Turkey Conference, 1973 (Folder 81)
  - Atatürk conference, 1973 (Folder 81)
  - Derek Hopwood, notes on Islamic reform movement, 1974 (Folder 81)
  - Don Quataert, 1973 (Folder 81)
  - Questionnaires, 1967 (Folder 81)
  - Amnesty International--Turkey, 1973 (Folder 81)
  - Hacettepe University, 1973 (Folder 81)
- Middle East Institute, 1968-1971 (Folder 81)
- Middle East Institute conference, 1971 (Folder 81)
- Clippings on the Middle East, 1970-1971 (Folder 81)
- Middle East Studies Association file (Folder 81)
  - Meetings, 1972 (Folder 81)
  - Meetings, 1974 (Folder 81)
  - Meetings, 1975 (Folder 81)
- Middle East Institute (Folder 82)
  - Conference materials and correspondence (Folder 82: 1)
  - Newsletter, 1972 (Folder 82: 2)
- Middle East Studies Association file (Folder 82-83)
  - Conference materials and correspondence (Folder 82)
    - 1970 (Folder 82: 3)
    - 1971 (Folder 82: 4)
    - 1971-1972 (Folder 82: 5)
    - 1973 (Folder 82: 6)
    - 1974 (Folder 82: 7)
  - Draft by-laws, 1966-1968 (Folder 82: 8)
  - Conference materials, Toronto, Canada, 1969 (Folder 83)
- Subject file (Folder 84)
  - Ankara University, 1973 (Folder 84: 1)
  - Bailey, Sidney D., 1969 (Folder 84: 2)
  - Benson, Robert, undated (Folder 84: 3)
  - Current Turkish Thought, 1973-1974 (Folder 84: 4)
  - Federation of University Teachers-Connecticut, 1974 (Folder 84: 5)
  - Hacettepe University, 1974 (Folder 84: 6)
  - Istanbul University, 1973 (Folder 84: 7)
  - Kapenga, Jay, 1974 (Folder 84: 8)
    Includes letter to Judge Soubhi Mahmassani from Reed
  - Middle East Studies Association, 1973 (Folder 84: 9)
  - Middle East Technical University (METU), 1973 (Folder 84: 10)
  - Okyar, Osman, 1973 (Folder 84: 11)
  - Pendle Hill, 1973 (Folder 84: 12)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, undated (Folder 84: 13)
  - Roos, Leslie L., 1971 (Folder 84: 14)
  - Skiotis, Dennis, 1974 (Folder 84: 15)
  - Sönmez, Emel, undated (Folder 84: 16)
  - State University of New York (SUNY) at Binghampton-Southwest Asian and North African studies, 1974 (Folder 84: 17)
  - Turkey, 1974 (Folder 84: 18)
  - Union for Experimenting Colleges and Universities, undated (Folder 84: 19)
  - U.S.I.S. Turkey, 1974 (Folder 84: 20)
  - University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) Near Eastern Center, 1972 (Folder 84: 21)
  - West, Steven L., 1973 (Folder 84: 22)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1974 (Folder 84: 23)
  - Printed matter (Folder 84-85)
    - Education in the Arab States, Arab Information Center, 1967 (Folder 84)
    - Directory of Fellows, Society for Values in Higher Education, 1978 (Folder 84)
    - American Council of Learned Societies Newsletter, 1977 Spring-Summer (Folder 84)
    - Constitution of the Society for Iranian Studies, 1968 (Folder 84)
    - The Garland Library of War and Peace, 1971 (Folder 85: 1)
    - American University of Beirut Newsletter, 1981 (Folder 85: 1)
    - Camp David: A New Balfour Declaration, Association of Arab-American University Graduates special report no.3, 1979 (Folder 85: 1)
- United Nations Children's Fund reports, 1974-1976 (Folder 85: 2)
- The Middle East: Back to Basics conference, Princeton University, 1982 (Folder 85: 3)
- Peace, 1979-1981 (Folder 85: 4)
- University of Connecticut file (Folder 85-86)
  - Office for International Education and Development (Folder 85-86)
    - International studies in Connecticut, undated (Folder 85: 5)
    - Overseas academic programs, 1978 (Folder 85: 6)
    - "The University in a Free Enterprise Economy" conference, 1982 (Folder 85: 7)
    - "The Role of the University in Turkey and the Changing Middle East,", 1982 (Folder 85: 8)
  - Research Foundation grant supplement request, 1978 (Folder 85: 9)
  - Undergraduate International Studies Program abstract, rough drafts, 1979-1981 (Folder 86: 1)
  - Dr. Nejat F. Eczacibasi visit to University of Connecticut, 1984-1985 (Folder 86: 2)
- Turkish Studies file (Folder 86)
  - Turkey Ministry of Commerce report, 1978 (Folder 86: 3)
  - "Survey of Management Training Institutions and Management Consulting in Turkey," Turkish Management Association, 1973 (Folder 86: 3)
  - International Symposium on Atatrk Reforms, 1973 (Folder 86: 4)
  - Notes on Turkish foreign policy and education law, 1982 (Folder 86: 4)
  - Turkish studies miscellany, 1987 (Folder 86: 5)
  - Directory of Active Fellows 1968-1987, Society for Values in Higher Education (Folder 86: 6)
  - Clippings regarding Israel and Jordan, 1982 (Folder 86: 7)
  - Hollingsworth, J. Rogers. "Perspectives on Social Development: The North Atlantic Community," presented at conference on the Development of Trends in Turkey, Hacettepe University, 1974 (Folder 86: 8)
  - Economics and oil, 1974 (Folder 86: 9)
- United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (Folder 86)
  - "Bulletin of Economic Development Number 14: Special Reports on Jordan,", 1956 July (Folder 86: 10)
  - "Jordan-Valley Agricultural Economic Survey,", 1954 October (Folder 86: 11)
- Personal correspondence and photographs, 1985-1986 (Folder 87: 1-2)
- Subject file (Folder 87)
  - Academe, 1986 (Folder 87: 3)
  - American Friends Service Committee pamphlet, undated (Folder 87: 4)
  - Eczacibasi, Nejat, 1984 (Folder 87: 5)
  - Friends World College, 1983-1985 (Folder 87: 6-7)
  - Heper, Metin, 1986 (Folder 87: 8)
  - International College, Beirut, reunion, 1985 (Folder 87: 9)
  - Köni, Hasan, 1986 (Folder 87: 10)
  - Middle East Libraries Association. "Cooperation Among Middle East Libraries of North America,", 1975 (Folder 87: 11)
  - New England Yearly Meeting of Friends, 1985 (Folder 87: 12)
  - United Nations Children's Fund reports, 1975 (Folder 87: 13)
- Turkish Studies file. Institute for Turkish Studies grant proposal and related documents, 1979-1986 (Folder 88: 1-5)
- University of Connecticut, Department of History events, 1986 (Folder 88: 6)
- Miscelleny, undated (Folder 88: 7)
- University of Connecticut file (Folder 89-91)
  - United States International Communications Agency (USICA) (Folder 89-90)
    - Middle East project proposal, 1979-1981 (Folder 89: 1)
    - Turkey project proposal documents, 1981-1983 (Folder 89: 2-6)
    - Turkey project proposal documents (Contd.) (Folder 90: 1)
    - Private sector correspondence, 1982 (Folder 90: 2)
    - R. T. Curran correspondence, 1981-1982 (Folder 90: 3-4)
    - Guidelines, 1978 (Folder 90: 5)
  - Course materials for HIST 205 taught by Howard A. Reed, 1985 (Folder 90: 6)
  - Notes, 1981-1982 (Folder 90: 7)
  - University of Connecticut Foundation, 1984-1985 (Folder 91: 1)
  - "Roles of the University in Turkey and in the Changing Middle East,", 1981 (Folder 91: 2)
  - Personnel file (Folder 91)
    - Travel claims and expenses, 1985 (Folder 91: 3)
    - Employment, 1982 (Folder 91: 4)
- Subject file (Folder 91-92)
  - Egypt, 1983 (Folder 91: 5)
  - Sabanci Holding, 1982 (Folder 91: 6)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1981 (Folder 91: 7)
    Mahmoud M. Safar and Abdullah Nasseef
  - Sheraton Corporation, 1983 (Folder 91: 8)
  - Turkey Conference, 1981-1983 (Folder 91: 9-15)
  - Turkey trip report, 1983 (Folder 91: 16-17)
  - Union Carbide, 1983 (Folder 91: 18)
  - Uniroyal, Inc., 1982 (Folder 91: 19)
  - United States Information Agency (Folder 92)
    - Grant approval, 1982 (Folder 92: 1)
    - Turkey, 1982 (Folder 92: 2)
  - United Technologies biographies, 1983 (Folder 2: 3-4)
  - Friends World College, 1984 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Middle East peace, 1984 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Islam, 1980-1983 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Middle East--Nuclear weapons, 1984 (Folder 2: 8)
    Includes publication of the American Friends Service Committee, "The Militarization of the Middle East" by Max Holland
- Turkish Studies file (Folder 92-93)
  - Turkey research materials, 1981-1983 (Folder 92: 9-10)
  - Printed matter, journals and textbooks, 1967-1986 (Folder 93)
  - White House briefing notes for the American Turkish Association, 1984 (Folder 93)
  - Turkish newspapers, 1982-1984 (Folder 93)
    - Forum, 1982-1984 (Folder 93)
    - Hürriyet, 1984 (Folder 93)
    - New Spot, 1984 (Folder 93)
- Subject file (Folder 94)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1983-1984 (Folder 94: 1-2)
  - American Universities Field Staff (AUFS) reports, 1977-1979 (Folder 94: 3-5)
  - Assembly of Turkish American Association (ATAA), 1984 (Folder 94: 6)
  - Kline, David, 1983 (Folder 94: 7)
  - Lisle Fellowship, 1983-1984 (Folder 94: 8)
  - Pendle Hill, 1984-1985 (Folder 94: 9)
  - Printed matter. Booklets and journals, 1983-1984 (Folder 94: 10)
- Personal correspondence, 1983 (Folder 94: 11)
- Reed, Howard A. "Turkey Restoring Democracy,", undated (Folder 94: 12)
- Conference materials. "The University in a Free Enterprise Economy,", 1984 (Folder 94: 13)
- Personal correspondence, 1983 (Folder 94: 14)
- Pamphlets and brochures, 1974-1981 (Folder 95: 1)
- Friends World College, 1984 (Folder 95: 2)
- Conference materials (Folder 95)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1967 (Folder 95: 3)
  - CENTO Conference of University Rectors on the Role of the University in Economic Development, Tehran, 1974 (Folder 95: 4)
  - Conference papers and related materials on Turkey and the Middle East, 1979-1984 (Folder 95: 5-6)
- Palestine studies, 1983 (Folder 95: 7)
- Institute of Turkish Studies correspondence, 1984-1986 (Folder 95: 8)
- "Strength Through Wisdom: A Critique of U.S. Capability, A Report to the President from the President's Commission on Foreign Language and International Studies,", 1979 November (Folder 95: 9)
- Article on Ayatollah Khomeini in Time, 1980 (Folder 95: 10)
- Professional papers on international education, 1964-1965 (Folder 96: 1-5)
- University of Connecticut History Department. Student papers and memoranda, 1984 (Folder 96: 6)
- Printed matter (Folder 97-98)
  - Journals, newsletters, and monographs relating to education and the Middle East, 1960-1984 (Folder 97)
  - Hürriyet, 1983-1984 (Folder 98)
  - New York Times advertisement supplement on Turkey, 1981 (Folder 98)
  - Treasures of Pakistan, catalog published by National Bank of Pakistan, circa 1981 (Folder 98)
- Personal correspondence, 1983 (Folder 98)
- Pedle Hill, 1984 (Folder 98)
- Turkish Studies Association handbook on Turkey, 1988 (Folder 98)
- National Education of Turkey consultant file, 1983-1999 (Folder 99-113)
  - American Council on Education conference materials, 1990-1992 (Folder 99)
  - UNICEF brochures, 1991-1993 (Folder 99)
  - National Center for Education Statistics publications, 1990-1991 (Folder 99)
  - Harvard Assessment Seminars reports, 1990-1992 (Folder 99)
  - International Association of the Evaluation of Educational Achievement (IEA) Guidebook, 1991 (Folder 99)
  - Œuvres hospitalires franaises de l'ordre de Malte, 1993 (Folder 99)
  - National Center for Education Statistics publications, 1990-1994 (Folder 100)
  - Report on Turkish economy, 1992 (Folder 100)
  - American-Turkish Friendship Council conference, 1992 (Folder 100)
  - "Solving the Math Problem: Exploring Mathematics Achievement in Japanese and American Middle Grades,", 1991 (Folder 100)
  - "The Turkish M & A Environment," Morgan Stanley report, 1991 (Folder 101)
  - National Center for Education Statistics publications, 1990-1994 (Folder 101)
  - International Assessment of Educational Progress publications on math and science, 1992 (Folder 101)
  - Pew Case Studies in International Affairs, 1994 (Folder 101)
  - World Bank report for Hungary, 1991 (Folder 102)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Folder 102)
  - Turkey research materials, 1991 (Folder 102)
  - Carnegie Foundation publications, 1990-1991 (Folder 102)
  - Ohio State University Education Research and Development Department (ERDD) correspondence and reports, 1992-1993 (Folder 102)
  - King Faisal School, 1991 (Folder 102:)
  - King Faisal School, 1991 (Folder 102)
  - Coalition of Essential Schools publications, 1992 (Folder 103)
  - Books on Turkish economy, 1989-1992 (Folder 103)
  - Books on education in the United States, 1992 (Folder 103)
  - Booklets of speeches by Turkish president Turgut Özal, 1989-1993 (Folder 104)
  - Education printed matter, 1990-1993 (Folder 104)
  - Turkish magazines, 1991-1993 (Folder 104)
    Includes Millî Eğitim published by the Turkish Ministry of Education
  - 21. Yüzyila dogru Türkiye: Gelecege dönük bir atilim stratejisi, volumes 1-4, 1991-1993 (Folder 105)
  - Book of genealogy for the Reed family, undated (Folder 105)
  - Book of genealogy for the Reed family, undated (Folder 105)
  - Middle East Studies Association meeting booklets, 1991-1993 (Folder 105)
  - Journal of Human Sciences, Middle East Technical University, 1987-1989 (Folder 106)
  - Education printed matter, 1984-1992 (Folder 106)
  - Ibn Khuldoon National School yearbook, 1983 (Folder 107)
  - IMF magazine, special issue on Turkey, 1990 (Folder 107)
  - World Development Report: Development and the Environment, 1992 (Folder 107)
  - "Kara Kum Integrated Poultry Company Joint Venture Agreement Between the Government of the Republic of Turkmenistan, the Ministry of Agriculture of the Republic of Turkmenistan and Kara Kum Poultry International, Inc.," draft, 1993 September (Folder 107)
  - United Arab Emirates Higher Colleges of Technology, 1993 (Folder 107)
  - Education printed matter, 1983 (Folder 107)
  - United States Coalition for Education for All files, 1993 (Folder 108)
  - Turkish economy printed matter, 1987-1989 (Folder 108)
  - Turkish education statistics, 1990 (Folder 108)
  - World Development Reports on Poverty and the Challenge of Development, 1990-1991 (Folder 109)
  - Directories, 1989-1996 (Folder 109)
  - Turkish economy surveys, 1996-1997 (Folder 109)
  - Aramco World magazines, 1997-1999 (Folder 109)
  - Middle East Studies Association of North America meeting, 1995; 1999 (Folder 109)
  - Turkish economy and education printed matter, 1995-1998 (Folder 110)
  - Middle East Studies Association conference booklet, 1996 (Folder 110)
  - MESA Newsletter, 1996-1998 (Folder 111)
  - Turkish education and economy printed matter, 1992-1998 (Folder 111)
  - Middle East Affairs Journal, vol. 4 no. 3-4, 1998 (Folder 111)
  - The Economist Conferences, Turkish Energy Conference, 1997 (Folder 111)
  - Wellington Yearbook, 1993-1996 (Folder 111)
  - Middle East Studies Association paper proposals, 1999 (Folder 112)
  - Travelearn program materials (Folder 112-113)
    - Egypt, 1996 (Folder 112)
    - Turkey, 1996-1997 (Folder 112)
    - Turkey, 1995 (Folder 113)
    - Greece, 1997 (Folder 113)
  - Congressional Research Survey (CRS) reports on Turkey, 1995-1996 (Folder 113)
  - "Turkish Studies Development Proposal Submitted to the Government of the Republic of Turkey,", 1993 (Folder 113)